本字幕由 ShinY 深影字幕组 原创翻译制作
深影字幕组论坛地址 http://shinybbs.com
翻译： 扑倒莫莫的小米  魔法莉露姆  Shadow  红鼻子的UFO
校对|后期： 莫若谦   时间轴： 莫若谦
彼得?
Pete?
我想我病了
I think I'm sick.
你一晚上都睡这儿?
Did you sleep in here all night?
我不想传染给你
I didn't want to get you sick.
还有就是 我得离厕所近点儿
Plus, I needed to be near a toilet.
我们结婚了呢
And now we're married.
几点了
What time is it?
我得陪沃伦参加考察活动
I have to chaperone Warren's field trip.
对 就是发烧了
Yep. Fever.
你哪儿都别去
You're not going anywhere.
你能把一整个班的二年级生都传染了
You could wipe out an entire class of sophomores.
管什么二年级生呢
Nobody cares about sophomores.
不 回你那充满病菌的浴缸里躺着 行吗
No, get back in your germ tub, all right?
你好好待着
You're staying here.
我来去考察活动
I'll go on the field trip.
- 谢谢 - 小事儿
- Thank you. - Of course.
还有一件事儿 黛安她也去
Oh, one more thing... Diane is also chaperoning.
- 你在笑吗 - 什么
- Are you smiling? - Uh, what?
- 你刚刚是笑了吗 - 好吧 一下下啦
- Did you just smile? - Well, maybe a little.
我 我已经盘算着怎么才能不去好几个礼拜了
I I-- I've been wanting to get out of it for weeks.
就是不知道怎么办 直到
I just didn't know how until to--
你干什么呀 打电话找医生吗
What are you doing? Are you calling a doctor?
不 找医疗者[用迷信方式治病的人]
No, uh, a healer.
嗨 杰基我是凯特
Hi. Jackie, it's Kate.
- 不要啊 - 是这样 彼得今天身体不太舒服
- No. - Listen, Pete's not feeling very well today.
你能来看看他嘛
Could you come by and check on him?
不要啊 我错了
No. I'm sorry I smiled.
我不该笑 我收回 拜托
I take the smile back. Come on.
你当然可以用我们的榨汁机榨树叶汁
Oh, of course you can put leaves in our juicer.
再见
Bye.
你让我见黛安 我给你找杰基咯
I see your Diane, and I raise you a Jackie.
来个人杀了我吧
Can someone come in and kill me?
花瓶娇妻 第一季第09集
要去参加活动了 你激动吗
You excited about the field trip?
当然啦 考察都是装装样子的
Yeah, it's fake school.
我可存了所有的零用钱准备去礼品店呢
And I saved up all my allowance for the gift shop.
你想在礼品店买什么
What do you want to buy at the gift shop?
我也不知道 凯特
Aw, gee, I don't know, Kate.
买个让你听起来像青蛙的哨子怎么样
Oh, how about a whistle that makes you sound like a frog?
你兴奋吗
Are you excited?
是啊 我要对着孩子们大吼大叫 跟你妈共处一室
Yeah, I get to yell at kids and hang out with your mom...
整整八个小时 还是在博物馆里
For eight hours... in a museum.
你在担心她会让你觉得自己很没文化 对吧
You're worried about her making you feel stupid, aren't you?
好吧 谢了 沃伦
Oh. Well, thanks, Warren.
我还没这么想过呢
I hadn't thought of that angle.
有时候我只想她对我和善一点
Sometimes I just wish she were a little nicer to me.
- 她可能需要来点儿吧 - 沃伦
- Maybe she needs to get some. - Warren!
这想法太赞了
That's a great idea.
但你不应该说那个
But you shouldn't be saying that.
听着 凯特我们都是成年人了
Oh, look, Kate, we're both adults here,
我觉得这完全是常识嘛
And I think it's common knowledge
来点儿 更轻松
that when people get some, they relax.
是啊 我知道
Yeah. I know.
只是听到你谈论你老妈的性生活 我震惊了
I'm just surprised to hear you talk about your mom having sex.
"来点儿"是这意思?
That's what "Get some" Means?
那你觉得是什么意思
What'd you think it meant?
我不知道啊 来点儿薯条 来条毯子
I don't know -- get some chips, a blanket,
只要是让你开心的东西都行
whatever makes you happy.
就是 "来点儿" 后面的词随便填
You know, "Get some..." Fill in the blank.
沃伦 那就是性生活的意思 没事儿
Warren, it means "Sex," And that's okay.
你知道的 一个人性生活规律了
You know, when -- when people are getting it on the regular,
就会冷静下来
they chill out.
坦白的说 你的想法很好
And frankly, your idea's a good one.
- 你妈需要来点儿 - 性生活
- Your mom needs to get some... - sex.
是的
Exactly.
她需要来点儿性生活
She needs to get some sex...
好了
All right.
和老爸以外的男人
...with another man.
嘿 有什么事儿吗 伯特
Hey, everything okay, Bertie?
你会模仿老爸的签名吗
Can you sign dad's signature?
这个得看情况
Now, that depends.
是考察活动还是因为你干坏事儿了
Is it for a field trip or because you're in trouble?
- 坏事儿 - 那不行
- Trouble. - Then no.
那就是考察活动好了
Then field trip.
好吧 你干什么了
Okay, what did you do?
"伯特连续两天都不能有课间休息
"Bert has had to sit out of recess two days in a row
因为他经常用一些愚蠢的行为打断课堂"
For interrupting class with excessive silliness."
你都干什么了
What were you doing?
没什么啊
Nothing.
就是安静的看书
Just reading quietly,
偶尔跳个小舞 做几个伯特翻
sometimes a little dancing, a few bertwheels.
伯特翻?
Bertwheels?
就和侧手翻差不多 但一边翻一边叫
They're like cartwheels but with screaming.
你老师是维切山姆女士 对吧
Ms. Wickersham's your teacher, right?
- 是的 - 她以前是我老师
- Yeah. - She was my teacher.
很喜欢我
She adores me.
你老姐我要来救你了
Your big sister's gonna hook you up.
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
伯特翻
Bertwheels!
看看是谁萎靡不振的样子呀
Whoa. Look who hit the wall real hard.
幸好我下了猛料
Wow, I'm glad I sold high.
好 太完美了
Okay. Perfect.
我不要喝那个
I am not drinking that.
好吧
Okay.
事情是这样的
So, here's the deal. Cool?
不管从哪个洞
This is gonna go in you,
我都会把这东西灌进去
one hole or another.
我还是用嘴喝吧
I choose mouth.
我喝下去你就走吗
If I drink this, you'll leave?
是的
Uh, yeah. Mm.
喝 喝 喝
More. More. More.
慢走不送
Bye-bye.
我得留下来 一小时后检查瞳孔
I have to stay and check your pupils in an hour --
确保我用对了蘑菇
Make sure I used the right kind of mushroom.
- 用对了蘑菇? - 是啊
- Right kind of mushroom? - Yeah.
给我
Give me that.
不要说话 好吗
No talking. Okay?
因为你需要休息
'cause you need to rest.
他们穿越了路桥 到这儿定居
They crossed the land bridge, and they came and settled here.
你们有五分钟时间去看看
So you've got five minutes to go look
蒙古建筑物 好吗
at the Mongolian structure, okay?
- 嗨 黛安 那么 - 凯特很好
- Hi, Diane. So -- - Kate, good.
我的想法是这样的
This is what I need --
A小队的孩子们现在应该要从鸟类展馆出来了
"A" kids should be coming out of the hall of birds right now.
然后我们让其中一半去鲸类馆
Then we'll send half of them up to the whales
另一半去亚洲织锦馆 好吗
and the other half down to the Asian tapestries, okay?
- 好的 - 很好
- Okay. - Good.
那么 周末如何呀
So, how was your weekend?
无论如何 我刚去过洗手间
Anyway, I just went to the bathroom,
现在你去的话刚刚好
so now's a good time for you to go.
然后就召集B队的学生 检查作业纸
Then we will round up group "B," check the work sheets,
确保没人作弊
Make sure they're not cheating,
然后我会偷听C组的情况
And I will eavesdrop on group "C."
偷听
Eavesdrop?
是的 凯特百分之九十的监护在于预防
Yes, Kate, 90% of chaperoning is prevention.
雅各布想要猥亵 一只恐龙
Jacob wanted to feel up...a dinosaur.
我偷听就是为了预防这个
My eavesdropping prevented that,
现在他要坐早班巴士回家了
And now he is going home on the early bus.
- 说到猥亵 - 嘘
- Speaking of feeling up -- - Shh.
青少年 偷听
Teenagers. Eavesdropping.
嘿 黛安
Oh, hey, Diane.
看到那对情侣没
Look at those two lovebirds, huh?
就算是几百年 几千年前
Even all those hundreds of... thousands of...
无论多久 爱情都能战胜一切啊
So long ago, love conquered all.
我是说 看她的脸
You know? I mean, look...look at her face.
她看上去那么的开心 满足
She's so happy and satisfied and...
- 凯特 - 怎么了
- Kate. - Yeah?
去厕所吧
Go to the bathroom.
有电话
Phone.
C组
Group "C."
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
是我 我在用家里的电话
Hey, it's me. I'm on the house phone.
我没多少时间了
I don't have a lot of time.
我 我现在衰爆了
I'm...I'm really in trouble here.
我需要你赶快回家 把杰基
I need you to come home and get Jackie...
凯特
Kate?
彼得
Pete?
凯特喂
Kate? Hello?
我是不是说过 不要跟任何人说话
What did I say about not talking to anybody?
我只是给凯特打个电话
I was just calling Kate.
好吧 那不要再打了
Well, don't do it again,
因为你需要休息 小傻瓜
'cause you need your rest, silly.
什么是草食动物
What is a herbivore?
嘿 沃伦
Hey. Warren.
我们正在分组学习
Oh, we...we were working in groups.
拿着 把这些包起来
Here. Go wrap this up.
- 多谢啦 - 好的 听着
- Thanks, man. - Okay, listen.
你擅长做媒吗
How good are you at matchmaking?
- 我们要替谁牵线搭桥啊 - 你娘
- Who are we making match? - Your mom.
- 我娘 - 是啊 你能做到吗
- My mom? - Yeah. You cool with this?
没问题
Yeah, sure.
反正去礼品店之前还有好几个小时的时间
It'll kill some hours before we go to the gift shop.
看
Look at this.
电视
Tv.
电子书
An electronic book?
你难道不明白 这种电子垃圾
Don't you realize all this modern crap
就是你生病的源泉吗
is the reason that you're sick to begin with?
也许是因为我的秘书在我眼睛里打喷嚏呢
Or maybe it's because my secretary sneezed in my eye.
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
你一周八十个小时都在你死我活的商业竞争中
You rat-racers with your 80-hour work weeks.
看看我 我一周只工作五小时
Look at me...I work five hours a week,
我从没生过病
And I've never been sick.
杰基我真觉得你该走了
Jackie, I really think you should go.
我不想把病传染给你
I don't want to get you sick.
哦 你没听见我刚说的话吗
Oh, did you not hear what I said?
我说我从没生过病
I said I have never been sick.
知道你需要什么吗
You know what you need?
你需要待在包的紧紧的襁褓中
You need a nice tight swaddle.
不 求你了 别把我包起来
No, please. Don't swaddle.
我想要动一动
I want to move.
- 好了 - 杰基
- There we go. - Jackie.
找回做婴儿的感觉了吧
Back to the womb for you.
杰基
Jackie.
这儿的水肯定有某种魔力
Oh, there has got to be something in the water here,
因为 维切山姆夫人 您看上去还是那么年轻啊
'cause, Ms. Wickersham, you have not aged a day.
见到你真高兴 你在这干嘛呢
It's so nice to see you. What are you doing here?
你看到了 就是送我弟弟上学啊
Oh, you know, just walking my little brother to school.
我是她异母
I'm her brother from another mother...
异父的弟弟
And father.
我姐跟我说你可喜欢纸杯蛋糕了
My sister told me how much you love cupcakes,
所以我们给你做了些
So we made you some.
是的 我们从头学的
Yes, and from scratch.
- 也不太难 - 好贴心啊
- No biggie. - Very thoughtful.
凯特这是雷
Kate. This is Leigh.
他喜欢旅游 日本文化 和艾恩・兰德[一位俄国流亡作家]
He loves travel, Japanese culture, and Ayn Rand.
他就是我妈的理想对象
He's kind of the perfect man for my mom.
我不是男人
I am not a man.
抱歉
Yeah. Sorry.
真可惜 她那么完美
Bummer. I mean, she was perfect.
莎拉 赛斯 斯图尔特 你们坐一桌
Sarah, Seth, Stuart, you're a table.
塔拉 特雷西 维克多 你们坐一桌
Tara, Tracey, Victor, you're a table.
可我想跟麦迪逊和艾丽卡一起坐
But I want to sit with Madison and Alexa.
你在这没有特权 坐好了
You have no leverage here. Sit down.
请不要跑
Walk, please.
嗨 我叫凯特也是一个监护人
Hi. I'm Kate. Also a chaperone.
鲁斯 布拉德利 莫里森
Russ Bradley Morrison.
哦 布拉德利 鲁斯 莫里森的爸爸吗
Oh. Brady Ross Morrison's father?
对
Yeah.
能不能先别吃 三明治呢
Don't let me keep you from your...sandwich?
不对 只是两片面包和番茄酱
Nope, that's just two pieces of bread and ketchup.
我能跟你坐一起吗
May I join you?
我认为监护人分开坐
I think it's more efficient
更方便 你不觉得吗
If the chaperones spread out, don't you?
是啊 完全同意
Yeah, totally.
好的 鲁斯 你是干什么工作的呢
So, Russ, what do you do for a living?
- M&A - 综合格斗术
- M and a. - Mixed martial arts?
企业兼并与收购
Mergers and acquisitions.
哇 还是很酷
Wow. Also cool.
那你平时有啥业余爱好呢
And does that leave time for any hobbies?
划船
I row.
好哎 哇 酷
Great. Wow. Cool.
呃 您太太她也划 划船吗
And, uh...and does your wife row...row?
我离婚了
I'm divorced.
我前妻觉得我事业心太强 压力太大了
My ex-wife thought I was too high-achieving and intense.
太棒了
That's perfect.
抱歉 貌似我们来晚了
Sorry, looks like we're going in a different direction.
这是 一头哥伦比亚猛犸象
This is Oscar, our Colombian Mammoth.
你在黑暗的巷子里绝对不想碰到的家伙
Wouldn't want to run into one of these guys in a dark alley.
- 他会吃了你 - 我质疑
- He might eat you. - Highly doubtful.
哥伦比亚猛犸象是食草动物
Uh, Colombian Mammoths were herbivores
一天能吃多达300磅的植物
That consumed up to 300 pounds of vegetation a day.
好的 我会核实下
Well, I'll definitely check on that.
好 你去核实吧
Okay. You go check.
嘿 黛安
Hey, Diane.
不好意思打断一下你偷听
Sorry to interrupt your eavesdropping.
听着
Get this.
我这个监护人真是尽心尽力
So, I'm chaperoning my brains out, okay?
我碰到另一个家长 看上去真的不错
And I meet this other parent who seems like a really great guy.
可爱 还单身
Cute and single.
你知道鲁斯 布拉德利 莫里森吗
Do you know Russ Bradley Morrison?
不 我也不想了解
No, and I don't want to.
真的
Really?
因为我觉得你们两个会很投缘的
'cause I feel like you two would really hit it off.
凯特难不成你觉得全世界都是做爱俱乐部
Ohh, Kate. Is all the world a sex club to you?
要拉皮条也是给别人
Go pimp someone else, please.
小家伙 你是怎么出来的
How did you escape, little boo?
我要去看病
I'm going to the doctor.
不不
No, no.
你不适合开车
You are in no condition to drive --
我给你加过东西后不行
Not after what I put in your system.
你说过冰沙胜过一切良方
You said the smoothie was all herbal.
确实如此 不过我在你的茶里放了一点可待因
It was, but I put an assload of codeine in your tea.
真搞笑 我得走了
That's ridiculous. I'm going.
我没事 绝对没有
I'm okay. Totally fine.
回床上去
Get back in bed.
伯特 这是你的课堂测验
Bert, here's your quiz.
谢谢 我想说
Thank you, and may I say
你现在和今早看起来一样美
you look as old as you did this morning?
谢谢
Thank you.
你想再来点家制纸杯蛋糕吗
Would you like some more homemade cupcakes?
或者给你一半我午餐吃的三明治
Or half my sandwich from lunch --
有奶油酪和果冻
It's cream cheese and jelly.
伯特 你是不是想被禁止休息
Bert, are you doing all this 'cause you don't want me
才这么做的吗
to keep you out of recess again?
对啊 希拉里告诉我的
Yes, Hillary told me to.
你很聪明 眼睛像海洋一样闪闪亮
And you're smart, and your eyes sparkle like the ocean.
要想要休息时间
All you have to do to get recess back
你只用管住身体 不要再做伯特旋转了
is control body and keep the bertwheels outside.
不必像这么个拍马屁的
You don't have to be such a suck-up.
- 拍马屁是啥 - 就是你姐姐
- What's a suck-up? - Your sister.
我不该这么说的
I shouldn't have said that.
这场对话没有发生过
This conversation never happened.
什么对话
What conversation?
啥 她真的这么说了
What? She actually said that?
对 不过这场对话从没发生过
Yeah, but this conversation never happened.
她说我拍马屁
She called me a suck-up?
你要干嘛
Where are you going?
我要去对维切山姆小姐臭骂一顿
I am going to give Ms. Wickersham a piece of my mind...
把这个苹果带给她
And bring her this apple.
黛安 你好
Hey, Diane.
我和沃伦要在附近散会儿步
Uh, me and Warren were gonna go roam around.
你也应该来的
You should come with.
然后放弃我即将获得去兰花厅的位置
And give up my place in line for the orchid pavilion?
多谢你喜感的消遣 凯特
Thanks for the comedy entertainment, Kate.
兰花厅
The orchid pavilion?
那可是博物馆的中心展品
Oh, it is the centerpiece of this museum,
每次只让少数人进去
And they only let in a few people at a time
以便最大限度地享受宁静之美
to maximize the tranquil beauty.
那好 去吧
Okay.Go.
站到队后去 继续
Back of the line. Go ahead.
沃伦 我们得让你妈妈还有鲁斯 布拉德利 莫里森
Warren, we have got to get your mom and Russ Bradley Morrison
一起去兰花亭
into the orchid pavilion together.
- 你在唱... 唱的是啥啊 - 没啥
- What are we -- what are we singing? - Never mind.
只是...我们的人呢
Just -- where's our man?
就在那边
Oh, right there.
不要吧 他们从来不会一同进去
Oh, no. They'll never get in at the same time.
那我在你前边
Oh, uh, I'm way ahead of you.
瞧我怎么让谣言四起的
Watch me crank up the rumor mill.
伙计们
Hey, guys. Guys.
在更新世岩厅要有一场打斗演出
There's gonna be a fight in the Pleistocene room.
相互转告 伙计们
Pass it on. Hey, guys.
在更新世岩厅要有一场打斗演出
There's gonna be a fight in the Pleistocene room.
更新世岩厅 走吧 快来
Pleistocene room. Let's go. Come on.
走吧 打打打
Let's go. Fight. Fight. Fight.
搞定
Get on it.
谢谢你
Thank you.
- 谢谢 - 尽情享受展览吧
- Thank you. - Enjoy the exhibit.
救命
Help.
有男人
A man.
你怎么下床了
How are you out of bed?
茶里的可待因都够让一头熊晕过去了
There was enough codeine in that tea to knock a bear out.
这些人是谁 他们在我家做什么
Who are these people? What are they doing in my house?
他们不是人
There's no people.
只是幻觉
That's a hallucination.
所以回去睡觉
So, go back to sleep.
- 睡觉 - 睡...
- Sleep. - Sl--
我命令你 睡觉
I command it. Sleep.
就是这样 鲁斯 布拉德利 莫里森.
That's right, Russ Bradley Morrison.
你知道你喜欢亲眼所见的
You know you like what you see.
中世纪的时候 兰花被看成春药
In the middle ages, orchids were considered an aphrodisiac,
但真正吸引我来到这里的
but the only thing turning me on in this room
是你裤套装的曲线
are the curves of your pantsuit.
像在印度遗产文化博物馆里那样吻我吧
Kiss me like you did at the Indian Heritage Museum.
在安哥拉洛奇后面
Behind the Potawatomi Lodge?
老天
Oh, my god!
怎...出什么事了
Wh-- what's going on?
你认识他
You know him.
不不 我不认识
Uh, no. No. I don't.
又来了 难以相信
Here we go again. Unbelievable.
她确实认识我 她非常了解我
She does know me. She knows me very well.
她一直是我的...
She's been to my condo...
因为我们互相见了两年了
Because we've been seeing each other for two years.
我可不是博物馆随便约炮的人
I am not a cheap museum booty call.
我是个男人 黛安
I'm a man, Diane.
鲁斯 布拉德利
Russ Bradley.
过去了
It's over.
很抱歉
Oh, I'm sorry.
我们每十分钟才开一次这扇门
We only open this door every 10 minutes
为了给兰花提供适当的湿度
to provide the proper, uh, humidity for the orchids.
所以你们还有六分钟
So you've got six minutes.
我不认识你
Well, I don't know about you,
不过我今天确实学到了很多兰花的知识
but I sure learned a ton about orchids today.
你怎么敢在插在我私事中间
How dare you meddle in my personal affairs?
黛安  我只不过想帮忙
Diane, I was just trying to help.
我是说 我以为你跟他很融洽
I mean, I thought you'd get along with him,
显而易见你们确实是...长达两年
which apparently you did... for two years.
我意思是 我们就不能在此承认吗 我都逮到了
I mean, can we just acknowledge here -- I nailed it.
贸易学校不教圆滑处事吗
Do they not teach tact in trade school?
你刚刚毁了我的恋爱 凯特
You just destroyed my relationship, Kate.
你想的都是什么
What were you thinking?
- 黛安 我... - 不不不
- Diane, I...  - No, no, no, no, no.
我确实想知道
I really want to know.
我想理解 像我研究洞穴人那样
I want to understand and study you
来研究你
the way I would study a caveman.
说实话 我只是想
Well, to be totally honest, I just thought
如果你有...伙伴关系
that if you were getting some...companionship,
可能你对我会好一点
that maybe you would be nicer to me.
我懂了
I see.
要是发生关系 我会放松下来
If I got laid, I might relax.
话不是这么说的
Well, not in those words.
如果我定期和人亲热一下
We might be friends, even,
我们甚至可能成为朋友
if I just got a little roll in the hay on a regular basis.
- 话绝对不是这么讲的 - 天呐
- Definitely not in those words. - Oh, god.
你为什么要搞地下情呢?
Why would you keep your relationship a secret?
我的意思是 你又不是要去参加竞选
I mean, it's not like you're running for office.
天呐 你要去竞选职位吗?
Oh, my god, are you running for office?
让我把某些事情跟你说清楚 凯特
Let me spell something out for you, Kate.
我做的每件事都很成功
I succeed at everything I do.
我失败过一次 我的婚姻
I had one failure -- my marriage.
我搞地下情
I kept this relationship private
是因为这是我的事
because it's my business.
我懂了
Ohh, I get it.
所以如果这段恋爱不顺利
And maybe if it didn't work out,
没人会知道你失败了
no one would have to know that you failed.
当我想知道拿铁里要放多少牛奶时
When I want to know how much milk to put in a latte,
我会问你的
I'll ask you,
所以直到那时 亲爱的 请别给我忠告
And until then, dear, no advice, please.
我从来没做过咖啡师
I was never a barista.
从未做过咖啡师
Never a barista.
我甚至不喜欢咖啡
Don't even like coffee.
该死的目标小组是什么东西?
What the hell is a goals group?
目标
G.O.A.L.S.
"以目标为导向的成熟女企业家"
"Goal-oriented adult lady entrepreneurs-s-s"
简称目标
G.O.A.L.S.
我们基本上是一个由未绝经的
We're basically a business support group
中年女人们所组成商业扶持小组
of women of a certain age who haven't yet gone through menopause.
看 我们通过鼓励和反复打气
See, we help each other achieve our goals
帮助彼此实现我们的目标
through encouragement and repetition and repetition.
- 你们谁有工作吗? - 我们有目标
- Do any of you people have jobs? - We have goals.
我的目标是完成我起头的事
My goal was to finish what I started.
所以 当我同意照顾你
So, when I agreed to take care of you
和护理你恢复健康
and nurse you back to health,
我清除了一切障碍
I didn't let anything get in my way.
你没有护理我恢复健康
You didn't nurse me back to health.
我的病比之前更严重了
I'm sicker than I was before.
你说得对 杰基他真的很悲观
Oh, you're right, Jackie. He's really negative.
没人... 没人让你发表意见
Uh, nobody... nobody asked you.
杰基你 你 你把我困在床上
Jackie, y-y-you trapped me in my bed.
你截断了我与外界的联系
You cut me off from the outside world.
你对我下药
You drugged me.
这 这像是"危情十日"的情节
Th-this is like the plot of "Misery."
你知道吗?
You know what?
我觉得你有点戏剧化了
I think you're being a little dramatic,
因为我所做的... 杰基所做的
because what I did... what Jackie did
是重新安排了她的整个日程表 好吗?
is rearranged her entire schedule, okay?
还有我想要一点点感谢语 目标
And I'd like a little bit of gratitude. Goals.
目标 目标 目标 目标 目标
Goals. Goals. Goals. Goals. Goals.
目标? 你们知道吗?
Goals? You know what?
你们... 你们知道我的目标是什么吗?
You... you want to know my goal?
我希望你们所有人十秒钟之内离开我的房子
I want all of you out of my house in 10 seconds,
不然 我就要打喷嚏 挠痒 咳嗽...
or I'm gonna sneeze, scratch, cough...
喘息 还有舔你们每一个人
wheeze, and lick every one of you.
我要把锁换了 把备层填满
I'm changing the locks, filling in the crawl space,
还要把狗洞用木板封住
and boarding up the dog door.
那些...
Well, that...
...没有帮助!
...won't help!
这谈话只需要一分钟 南希
This will only take a minute, Nancy.
刚开始 我对你说我是马屁精这事很生气
At first, I was offended that you called me a suck-up,
但一路骑车过来 我理解了有些事
but on the ride over here, I realized something.
你说我是马屁精 我觉得我是进取之人
What you call a "suck-up" I call a "go-getter."
所以我会继续做进取之人
So I am going to keep go-getting,
因为它会带领我去我想要去的地方
because it is going to go-get me places.
首先 它会带我进入大学
First, it's going to go-get me into college,
然后 它会带我进入法律学院
and then it's going to go-get me into law school,
最后 它会带我取得
and finally, it's going to go-get me a job
高等法院法官索尼娅 索托梅耶尔的书记员工作
clerking for Supreme Court Justice Sonia Sotomayor,
所以就去拍我的马屁吧
so suck up on that.
顺便说一下 这是给你的
By the way, this is for you.
这是有机苹果
It's organic.
你的妈妈生气了 这是我的错
So, your mom's mad, and it's kind of my fault.
我真心希望我能和她谈谈 但她根本不理我
And I really wish I could talk to her, but she won't listen.
她很记仇
That bites.
能给我点去买宇航员雪糕的钱吗?
Can I get some money for some astronaut ice cream?
过来
Come here.
为什么?
Why?
沃伦 我知道你害怕的东西
Warren, I know what you're afraid of.
- 剪刀 - 失败
- Scissors. - Failure.
不要试图去做完美无缺的人
Don't let trying to be perfect
而是只要自己开心就好
get in the way of you being happy.
我的意思是 当然 你可以为了保全面子
I mean, sure, you can play it safe
而永远不敞开心扉
and never put yourself out there,
但所有的这些只是你在害怕而已 你知道吗?
but all that really is, is you just being afraid, you know?
我的生活中常常发生美好的事情
Everything great that's ever happened in my life
是因为我愿意去丢脸受挫
has been because I've been willing to fall on my face.
你说的对 你知道吗?
You're right. You know what?
从现在开始 我不会化太多精力去变得十全十美
From now on, I'm not gonna focus so much on being so perfect.
不客气 去玩吧
You're welcome. Go play.
打扰一下?
Excuse me?
今天 天文馆节目的标题是
And now today's planetarium show,
"数学 太间的组成部分"
entitled "Math: The Building Block of Space."
不好意思?
Excuse me?
在我们开始之前
Um, before we begin,
我想说件事
there is something I'd like to say.
你们看到那位男士了吗?
Do you see that man?
我认识那个人
I know that man.
我认识他 而且和他交流过
I know him and have talked to him.
还有...
And...
我很享受和他的谈话
I enjoy talking to him.
在未来的某时
And I hope to talk to him again
我希望还能再次与他交谈
sometime in the future.
谢谢大家
Thank you.
说的真好 你做的不错
That was beautiful. You did great.
什么意思?
What?
谢谢你的帮助... 沃伦
Thank you for your help... Warren.
我要你
I want you.
来吧
Take me.
笑什么?
What?
据官方消息
It's official.
火星上无生命迹象
There's no life on Mars.
他们何时才能明白?
When will they ever learn?
几年前我就能告诉他们这事儿了
I could have told them that years ago.